Alberto Roque Carrizo Fernández

roquec.com github.com/roquec linkedin.com/in/roquec contact@roquec.com +34 645077965 Gijón, Spain

Introduction

I am an experienced software engineer with a pragmatic approach, valuing simplicity in solutions. Highly independent and adept at self-learning, I seek opportunities to deliver genuine value to clients and society. Currently I develop Windows desktop applications at Metrohm DropSens.

Skills

.NET C# Azure SQL WPF Elasticsearch Redis Git Docker Microservices GraphQL Powershell JavaScript

Experience

Feb 2024 - Present · Software Engineer at Metrohm DropSens (Precision instruments for chemical analysis)

- · Developing and maintaining components for highly reliable enterprise Windows application.
- · Leading efforts to introduce ELK monitoring solution via workshops and POC implementation.
- Using .NET C# WPF SQL DDD SpecFlow Scrum ELK gRPC

Sep 2018 - May 2022 · Senior Backend Engineer at NEOCLES (B2B e-commerce platform for fashion)

- Designed and built high-performance e-commerce APIs for thousands of concurrent users.
- · Managed releases and maintenance for 5 segregated client production environments.
- · Developed backend services receiving 10M+ import messages daily from external systems.
- · Led upgrade and configuration of 30+ Elasticsearch servers, saving thousands of euros monthly.
- · Worked directly with clients conducting fit-gap analyses to integrate new services and features.
- Used .NET C# SQL Elasticsearch Azure Redis Docker AKS Service Bus.

Jan 2017- Sep 2018 · Full-stack Developer at INVESTEL (Fleet management system)

- Led development of an AngularJS management application for internal use.
- Worked with designer on implementation of new Angular frontend for existing application.
- · Evolved into a full-stack developer role, addressing bugs and implementing new features in the backend.
- Implemented and documented OAuth service for external client authentication.
- Used AngularJS C# SQL .NET Framework Redis Mercurial.

Projects

Sep 2022 - Present · Ship Navigation Application · Winui3 C# .NET

- · Designed and build Windows desktop application based on clients requirements.
- Integrated with Automatic Identification Systems (AIS) via serial port connection.

Mar 2023 - Oct 2023 · Portfolio Website: roquec.com · Jekyll JavaScript SASS

- Developed custom JavaScript and SASS styling to imitate Visual Studio Code look and feel.
- · Automated deployments, Lighthouse testing and reporting using GitHub Actions and Powershell.

Education

2011 - 2016 · Bachelor's degree, Computer Software Engineering from University of Oviedo, Spain.

Languages

English (Full professional proficiency) and Spanish (Native).